To find the best credit cards,
we have created a detailed model in which
we have compared almost all the credit cards of India on 50 different parameters.
And we have found the best
credit cards in each category.  Dude, I'm
sure many of you have seen this model
before.  I have also asked for access to it in the comment section
and I am sure everyone will
want access to it.  So in this video
we have brought a great solution.  The solution is much
more interesting than what you are thinking.  In fact, you will
apply for any credit card in future.
I guarantee you,
watch this video till the end.  You are going to
benefit only.  In this video, we'll not
only tell you
which are the best credit cards of 2026, but you're also going to get
a great bonus.  Now
look friend, this is the first channel to create such a detailed model.
Be economical and in 2026 we are
taking things to the next level.  We are
bringing some super interesting and super
exciting things for you.  Along with this, of course we are going to talk
about the best credit
cards in 2026 in different categories.  But
before we start the video disclaimer.  We will
not cover 100% of the details in this video.
Ah, if we sit down to cover all the details, it will be a
1 hour video.
So we're going to focus on the
important points, the important things.  So
please do not comment that we have
not made it in detail.  We want to
give you as much information as possible.  You should be able to get
maximum value out of your time.  So first of all
we will start with the obvious category which is the
best credit card in
the lift free category.
Our obvious pick in this obvious category is the
Amazon ICICI Pay Credit Card.  I think it is the
only credit card in our list
that has maintained its position for the last 6 years.
I think this card has become everyone's favorite
and honestly it is one of my
favorite cards too.  I have been using this
card since 5 years now and I have never been
disappointed with it.  The main USP of this card is that it
offers 5% cashback
for Amazon Prime users.  3% for non-
Prime users and 2% cashback with merchant
partners.  Amazon Merchant Partners Like
McBMytrip, Dominos, Danzo, Uber, Urban
Company Etcetera.  In fact, there are 100 plus such
partners through whom you can earn this 2% cashback.
Apart from this, you get 1% cashback
in all other categories except Accept Fuel and Gold.
Amazon, ICICI
credit card one of the few cards which still
offers you 2% cashback on insurance
payments.  If it is paid via Amazon Pay.
If you do not pay through Amazon Pay,
you get 1% cashback on insurance
payments.  Now the only downside of this
card is that its acceptability
remains low.  The chances of meeting have reduced a bit.
Which is why it may not suit
everyone.  This is the only reason.  Alternatively I
would recommend Credit Pay Yes Bank
Aspe Credit Card.  This is very simple.
No nonsense UPI credit card with
decent rewards across all spend
categories and also it is one of the best
credit cards in the UPI category.
This card was offering you flat 2% cashback till 2025
on all your UPS spends
without any capping.  He has increased the 2% to
3% in 2026.  So Now You Get
Flat 3% Cashback on All Your UPS Pence.
But you will get this cashback only if you
make UPI payments through Credit Pay app.  Now, you might be wondering
why we are not recommending this Super Money Credit Card
?  It is also a life free
credit card.  Plus it offers you 5%
cashback.  Here I would like to clarify one thing.
Super Money Credit Card
comes in multiple variants.  One
with Cotter, one with AIS.  This 5%
cashback offer comes with Kotak
and that too only on MNTRA.  Normally Super
Money Credit Card offers you 3% cashback.
Credit Pay normally offers you 3% cashback.
But if your monthly spends
exceed Rs 25,000, you will get 5%
cashback on your UPI spends.  So if this was
not enough.
With this UPI cashback, you can earn discounts ranging from 6% to 24% on brands like Amazon P, Flipkart,
Swiggy, Zomato etc.
You will get shopping vouchers of these brands on
Credit
Pay app.  You can buy these vouchers using cashback and get a
discount of 6 to 24%.  To
apply for this card,
your minimum age should be 21.  Your
minimum salary should be ₹25,000 per month
and your minimum civil score should be
720.  Without this you will not get this card.
You apply for this card.
You will get a joining bonus of ₹1,000.  So
friend, this is like free money because the card is
free for your lifetime.  You are getting
₹1000 just for linking it to Credit Pay app.
The next category is best
credit cards for online food delivery and
grocery shopping.  Now we have noticed that in
the past three-four years, all of our expenses have
increased significantly in this particular category.  So we
have added this as a separate category this
year.  Now in this r first pick would be
Swigg HDFC Credit Card.  As a
welcome benefit with this card you get a
complimentary 3 month Swiggy 1 membership.
If you already have that membership, your membership will be
extended by 3 months.  Now the USP of
this card is there in which you are getting 10% cashback
on SWGI including food
orders, Instamar, Dine Out, Genie
etc.  Now man, we haven't seen any beginner's
card that gives you 10% cashback.
And the good part is that the
cashback limit in this is ₹1500 per month which
is really good.  Additionally you get 5%
cashback on online spends on
platforms like Nykaa, Myntra, Ola,
Uber, etc. with a monthly limit of ₹1500.
Apart from this, you are getting 1% cashback on all other payments
except fuel, rent, wallet
loading and EMI.
Honestly, it is one of those cards which have the
potential to become as popular
as Amazon Pay, ICICI card in the next
two to three years.  Although the annual fee for this card is Rs
500 plus GST, many people are
getting it for free.  Because every
time I open Swiggy, this card is
offered as lifetime free.  If you
spend ₹2000 to ₹3000 per month on
food delivery and grocery then this card
should be in your portfolio.  Ah, to apply for this card,
your minimum salary should be
₹25,000 per month and your civil
score should be ₹700 plus.  Now in this
category I would also like to recommend
HSBC Life Plus.  Ah this card gives
you a cashback of 10% on grocery, food
delivery and dining spends and 1.5% on
all other spends.  Now this card comes with
the joining fee and an annual fee of Rs 999
plus GST.  But if
you make a transaction of Rs 20,000 using this card in the first 30 days,
you get a cashback of Rs 1,000.
If you want to get the annual fee waived
off, you will have to
spend a minimum of ₹2 lakh in a year.  And this 10%
cashback you are getting on food delivery,
grocery and dining spends, you get it on
both online and offline spends.
Whose cap is ₹1000 per month which
in my opinion is quite decent.
If you maximize this, you
can save ₹10 to ₹12,000 in a year.  And
you also get one complimentary
domestic lounge access per quarter with this card.
Which in my opinion could have been
better.  But for what it offers I think
it's a recent card.  Even if you
spend ₹4 to ₹5000 per month on your food
delivery, grocery, dining etc., I
think this card is quite decent for that.
The next category is best cashback
credit cards in which there is a very
close competition between SBI Cashback and
HDFC Mallia.  Both of these cards offer you 5%
cashback on online shopping.  But in HDFC Millennium
you get maximum cashback of ₹1000 every month.
With SBI cashback, you
get a monthly benefit of ₹5,000.  And
in SBI cashback, you will get this 5% cashback on
almost all online shopping
platforms.  But
in HDFC Bank, you
get this 5% cashback only on Amazon, Flipkart and MNTRA.  So the
winner is SBI Cashback Credit Card.  Now
SBI Cash Back Credit Card is also one of the
best cashback credit cards in the
online shopping category for
online spends because it offers 5% cashback,
it is quite rare even for premium
cards category, otherwise if you
spend ₹2000-₹3000 online every month then
SBI Cashback Credit Card is a must have as well.
Now with SBI Cashback Credit
Card you get 5% cashback on
your online spends on platforms like
Amazon, MNTR, Swiggy, Zomato, etc
and you get 1% cashback on offline
spends.  Plus, to get this card,
you have to pay a joining fee of ₹99 plus GST.
Now if you spend ₹2000 online
you can earn ₹100 cashback per month.
Which means you can earn cashback of ₹1200 per year.
So by spending ₹2000 per month, you will
earn back the joining fee of ₹99 plus GST.  The
maximum limit for earning cashback is ₹5,000 per month which a
lot of people say is quite less.  But I think
this is not less.  This is quite decent as
to earn ₹5,000 cashback you will have to
spend ₹1 lakh every month.  Which I
think is quite sufficient for 99% of the
population.  Now friend, to get this card,
your annual plus joining fees is Rs
999 plus GST.  But if you
spend a minimum of ₹1 lakh in a year, then
your annual fee will be waived off.
Now, this card also has the same issue as Amazon
Pay ICICI, that it also has
low acceptability.  In that case, I would
recommend PhonePe SBI Select Black.
PhonePe has recently launched two new cards.
Select Black and Select Purple.   The
annual fee for Black is a bit higher
but its rewards are also better.  Now
PhonePe SBI Select Black offers you 10%
reward points on PhonePe spends
including recharges, bill payments,
insurance, flights, hotels. Monthly cashback
limit is maximum ₹2000 per month.  You also
get 5% cashback on many other brands
like Amazon, Myntra, Swiggy, Nykaa,
etc. and its maximum capping is
₹20,000 per month.
You also get a flat 1% cashback on other spends,
capped at ₹1000 per month.  Additionally,
you get four complimentary domestic launch access and a complimentary Priority Pass for international launch
access for the first two years.  For this
you have to pay $99 separately.  Now this
card comes with an annual fee of $1500
plus GST but that can be waived off.   The
reverse can happen if you
spend a minimum of ₹3 lakh in a year.  Additionally, if you
spend ₹5 lakh in a year, you
also get a reward of ₹5,000.  So far we have
shown you five to six cards.  Now we
will show five to six more cards.  But the real
question is did you understand
which is the best credit card for you?  And
90% of the people will say a big no.  Now to
solve this problem we have created Card
Match.  Now this is our first credit card
product.  This product is based on the algorithm we showed you in the beginning.
Now we could have shared that
boring Excel sheet with you but it
is difficult to understand.  Instead we build an entire
logic into card batch.  This product includes
a tool called Find My Card.
In this you can basically tell your details and
preferences.  As you can see,
we have stated our preferences in this.
And then this tool will now find the
perfect three to four cards according to
your preferences and recommendations.  And you
can also apply for this card from there.
Now friend, this is the first version of the card match.
So our
recommendations may not be perfect.  But our team is
actively working on it and improving it
every day.  Now you will get the link of the product
in the description and pin comment.
Along with card recommendation, this is also
a card discovery platform.  You
can search for the card here and apply from here.  We Have Handpicked The Top 60 To
70 Cards And We Have Added That In Card
Match.  Now I know there are many places where
you can apply for the card.  But
applying for a credit card through Card
Match makes a lot of sense.  Because this is the
only platform which offers you flat
₹250 cashback.  Ah on almost all the
cards for the first Fox.  Books and this
cashback of ₹250, we are
giving it to you from our pocket.  The bank is not offering you.
And just to be clear.  The bank
's own offers remain as it is.
We are giving you this cashback of ₹250 from our pocket.
So, you will definitely get the offers from the bank.
And you get this
cashback in the first 90 days of card issue.
So, this is exactly like free money.  So,
friend, if you are thinking of applying for any card
, please
do it through Card Match only.  You will get a cashback of ₹2.
Plus you will be supporting us in a very
big way.  Again the link will be
found in its description and the pin will be
found in the comment.  If B's ​​fight has
ever helped you in any form.
Please recommend Card Match to your friends
and family and help
us make the biggest card discovery
platform.  Now with this we move on
to our next category which is the
best travel card.  Last
year we picked Axis Atlas in this category.  In this
you used to get Axis H points.  And each
point was too worth it.  Now friend, its
reward conversion rate was so good
that it was quite profitable.  But
unfortunately it has been happening.
No Good Thing Lasts Forever in the Credit Card Industry.
Axis discontinued this card in late 2025.
And in
its place they have brought Axis Horizon.
Now Axis Ho Herzon can be thought of as a
downgraded version of Axis Allels.  Now
Axis Horn, its annual fee is Rs 3000 plus GST.
And along with this you
get 5000 Edge Miles.  Axis Atlas had a
1:2 convergence of edge miles.
Butt axis horizon gets a 1:1 convergence.
So these 5000 Edge Miles can be
converted to ₹5000 at various partners
like Air France, Marriott, Singapore
Airlines etc.  Talking about reward points,
you get five Edge Miles
on every ₹100 spent on
transactions like hotel and flight
bookings.  If you book via an Access Travel
Edge portal.  This is like 5% cashback if you
convert it via partner channels.  Now the
downside of this card is that you do
not get any spend based fee waiver or milestone benefit.  How ever you get a
decent number of latch visits.  You get 8
international and 8 domestic latch visits
in every quarter which I
think is more than enough.  Now in this category
I would like to give an honorary mention to
Indson Avius.  Indus AVs is a very
premium card which comes with an annual
fee of ₹10,000 plus GST.  In this you
get ₹0000 AVS points as a joining benefit.  Now, we cannot translate this conversion of two exactly.
But one point could mean two to 2.5 if you
play your cards right.  So effectively, you
can book flights worth ₹80,000 to ₹90,000 by paying a fee of ₹10,000 on Indus Air.
That's the magic of this card.  Moving on to our
next category which is the best
credit card in the premium category and
our pick in this is HDFC Infinia Metric.
Normally, you get a reward rate of 3.3% in HDFC Infinia
but if you
use it on Smart Buy portal, this can be as
high as 16.6%. Let me
explain how. Now,
you can easily make flight and hotel bookings on Smart Buy portal.
But the best part is that up to
70% of that amount can be paid via your
reward points.  And the remaining 30% will have to be
paid by card.  But the good
part is that whatever amount you pay through your card
on your Smart Buy portal, you will
also earn 16.6% reward points which
is like five times the normal reward
rate.  Now you can use these points again
for flight and hotel bookings.  Now friend,
I can't tell you how many
flights I have booked through my reward points.
Additionally,
Infinia has something called the Global
Value Program for international travel.  In this program you
get additional 1% cashback on international
spends.  Its maximum limit is ₹1 lakh
in one month.  Normally forex charges at HDFC
are 2% but with this extra 1%
your total reward rate is 4.3%.  So net net
you will end up making 2.3% on international
transactions.  With HDFC Infinia, you get unlimited domestic and international link access for yourself
and your add-on card holders.
Plus you get one
complimentary night stay and ITC One
Plus One on Buffen ITC Hotels
complimentary Club Barrier membership
global personal concierge etsetra.   The
SGS Infinia is however an invite-only
card.  And for this your monthly salary should be
minimum 2.5 to 3 lakh.  This Way The
Card Remains Very Very Exclusive.  Our
next category is the best utility
credit card.  In this your pick is Airtel,
Axis credit card.  Dude, in India there are very few
cards which offer you
cashback on monthly bill payments like
broadband, DTH, Wi-Fi, etc.  And
even fewer cards which offer you cash back
on utility bills like gas and
electricity.  Enter, Airtel, Axis,
Credit Card.  Now Airtel Access offers
you 25% cashback on mobile, broadband,
Wi-Fi details bill payments.  If you
make payment through Airtel Thanks app.
Its monthly limit is ₹250.  This means you will
get a 25% discount on a monthly bill of ₹1000.  Which in my opinion is
slightly low.  On top of this it also offers
you 10% cash back on all bill payments such as
gas and electricity.  As we
told earlier.  Only if it is paid via Airtel
Thanks app.  Its monthly limit is also ₹250.
Apart from this,
you get up to 10% cashback in Swig Zomato Big Basket.  Whose
maximum capping is ₹500 per month.
You get up to 1% cashback on the remaining spends.
Plus you get four complimentary
domestic lounge visits in one year.  The
annual and joining fee of this card is ₹500
plus GST.  But as soon as you pay the joining fee,
you get Amazon vouchers.
To get the worth ₹500 and annual fee waived off, you will have to spend a minimum of ₹2 lakh in a year.
I am sure that still many
people are confused as to which is the
perfect credit card for me?  Why am I
not able to understand after watching the entire video
?  If you are in the same situation, then please
go to card match.  The link is in the description.
Use the Find My Card tool.
Find the perfect credit card and
apply for that credit card via Card
Match only.  As a welcome benefit you are
getting a voucher of ₹250 for the first
applicants.  Also this ₹250 voucher
is separate from the bank offer.  Bank offers
remain as it is.  We are giving you this complimentary ₹250
from our side.
Edge a thank you for using card match.  Link will be
found in description, Pind will be
found in comment, Share link with your family
and friends, help us grow.  Share this
video with your family and friends.  Thank
you and advance.